NETFLIX オリジナルシリーズ
When I heard Kurose
had offered him this mission,
（白石(しらいし)）黒瀬(くろせ)さんから
このミッションに誘われたって
聞いたときね
I thought this might happen.
ひょっとしたらって思ったの
But I didn't stop him.
でも止めなかった
I knew that this was very important.
とても大切な仕事なんだって
分かってたから
That's why I'm taking part, too.
だから こうして私も参加した
This is the path he chose.
これは彼が自分で選んだ道
It's not your fault.
あなたのせいじゃない
（アイコ）うう…
Thank you for mourning him.
ありがとう 悲しんでくれて
Thank you.
ありがとう
〜
Is it really possible to use Cell
Assembler Two to treat wounds?
（一樹(かずき)）ケガの治療で
セル･アセンブラ２の投与なんて
ありえるんですか？
I thought the only case of their use
in a live body was on Dr. Kiryu.
（遙香(はるか)）
生身の人間への投与なんて
桐生(きりゅう)博士の事例だけかと思ってた
（一樹）
それでマスクなしで外 出ても
平気だったのか
No wonder Kanzaki is able to
survive outside without a mask.
神崎(かんざき)のヤツ
It's a good excuse
for testing on humans,
（遙香）体(てい)のいい人体実験だわ
since he's a pre-Burst victim.
バースト以前の被害者ってことね
Even so, what he said still pissed me off!
（楓(かえで)）
だったとしても
何 あの言いぐさ！
Accepting a life-threatening mission means
（雄哉(ゆうや)）
命懸けのミッションになる
ということは
that you're prepared to die
from the very start.
はなから覚悟の上で
引き受けていただいたはずです
Or maybe in your heart,
それとも 本心では
you weren't taking the threat
to your life seriously.
まさか命までは落とすまいと
タカをくくっていた と？
Is he trying to get rid of us?
私ら 降りさせようとでも
してんの？
だったら 絶対…
Then, I swear I'll--
（遙香）そう
（楓）ん？
That's right.
He knew if he said that, we'd be
too proud not to finish the mission.
ああ言えば 私たちは
意地でも最後までミッションを貫く
（２人）ん？
He knows us too well.
（相模(さがみ)）分かってんだよ ヤツは
Damn, that's one clever kid.
ったく どこまで食えねえガキだよ
-Do you trust him?
-What?
（白石）彼のこと信じてる？
（アイコ）え？
どこまで聞いてる？
今回のミッションのこと
How much have you heard
about this mission?
Well...
えっと…
Why didn't you tell me
（アイコ）
どうして教えてくれなかったの？
that when we get the real me,
私が本物の体を取り戻したら
the other me will disappear?
もう１人の私が消えちゃうって
あ… 白石さんに？
Shiraishi told you?
ホントなの？
Is it true?
本来あるべき形に戻るだけだ
I'm returning you to the way
you should be.
The human to the human,
人は人に
the artificial to the artificial.
作り物は作り物に
あっ 作り物…
Artificial...
そして その作り物は
Besides, that artificial part
is the cause of the Burst.
バーストを引き起こした
元凶でもある
Unless the cause is removed,
the Burst can't be ended.
元凶が消えなければ
バーストを収めたことにはならない
でも だって今の私のこの体が
その複製体なんでしょ？
But this body I have right now
is the duplicate, right?
それで夢でコンタクトしてる子が
この複製体の脳なんでしょ
And the girl that I contact in my dreams
is the duplicate brain, right?
その子が消えちゃうって…
But destroying her...
means killing her!
殺すっていうこと？
In simple terms, yes.
分かりやすく言えば そうだ
You'll be separated.
The process will reverse your creation.
作ったときと逆の過程で
分解するだけだ
The other you isn't human.
There's no need to sympathize with her.
相手は人間じゃない
思いやる必要はない
はっ…
This must be something
that I just can't understand.
きっと私には
分からない話なんだよね
You're doing something
that only you can understand, Kanzaki.
神崎君にしか分からないこと
しようとしてるんだもんね
It's okay for me to trust you, right?
信じて… いいんだよね？
（雄哉）人型？
Human forms!
Aiko!
（一樹）アイコちゃん！
All right, whatever happens,
we'll get you to Primary Point.
（相模）
いいだろう 何があろうと
プライマリー･ポイントまで
連れてってやる
ただしミッションが完了したあとは
赤の他人だ
But once this mission is over,
we're strangers again.
That's my intention.
そのつもりです
-Let's go, Aiko!
-Hey!
（一樹）行こう アイコちゃん
（雄哉）おい！
Tachibana, does it hurt?
（雄哉）橘(たちばな) 痛みは？
I didn't sense it! Why?
（アイコ）感じなかった　なんで？
This is strange.
（雄哉）
おかしい
マターの株が
もう１つあるということか
Is there another root Matter?
Activity in Area Five and Six!
（係員）当該エリアは ５ ６
この勢いだと
新たにダムを乗り越える危険性が
At this rate,
it'll overflow the dams again!
Tomorrow will be the seventh day
since we entered the Area.
（雄哉）
日付が変われば
エリアにダイブインして７日目だ
明日にはプライマリー･ポイントに
たどりつかなければ
We have to reach Primary Point tomorrow,
before the other you loses consciousness.
もう１人の君の意識がなくなる前に
I wonder what it will feel like
when I disappear.
（アイコ）
自分が消えちゃうって
どんな感じがするんだろう
There's no feeling when you disappear.
（雄哉）消える瞬間の感覚はない
It's just like falling asleep.
自分が眠りに落ちる瞬間を
自覚できないように
You won't know that
you've lost consciousness.
意識が無に帰せば
あとは ただ静かな眠りだ
The rest is tranquil sleep.
You talk as if you know about it.
知ってるみたいに言うのね
（南原(なんばら)）つまり伊佐津(いさづ)は
In other words,
大活性と柚葉(ゆずは)ちゃんとの
関連性を知っていた
Isazu knew the Matter's activity
and Yuzuha's are linked.
I always thought you two
shared everything.
君とヤツは
一蓮托生(いちれんたくしょう)だとばかり思ってたよ
I thought so, too. Until now.
私も 今の今まではね
あっ 見えてきた
最後の関門 Ｋ５！
I can see the final gate, K5!
（アイコ）あっ…
Beyond that wall is Kiryu
Biotech Research Facility Two.
（雄哉）
あの壁を越えた先が
桐生生命工学研 第二研究所
Primary Point!
プライマリー･ポイントだ
Okay, let's climb that giant dam!
さあ あのデケえダムを登るぞ
生き残っていたら また会おう
See you there, if we survive!
-Wilco!
（一同）ウィルコー！
Shiraishi and our two clients will take
the left ramp to the top of the dam.
（相模）
お客の２人は白石さんと一緒に
左手の斜路をたどって ダムの上へ
芹(せり)･三沢(みさわ)チームは
右手ダム基部の擁壁(ようへき)から
Seri and Misawa will go up the wall
from the right.
あ！
Kazuki and I will distract the Matter
as we climb up the front of the dam.
（相模）
俺と一樹は正面から
マターを陽動しながらダムを登る
はっ！
くっ
（一同）あ！
あっ…うっ
あっ
It's coming!
（アイコ）来る！
（雄哉）あっ…ん？
（アイコたち）うわっ
～
あっ…
（アイコ）え？
助けてくれたの？
It saved us?
（白石）マターが？
The Matter?
-Hurry!
-Let's go!
（相模）急げ！
（白石）行きましょう
（白石）
このダムにギロチンはない
This dam has no Guillotine.
The shock's effect is limited.
電撃の効果は限定的よ
Prepare yourself.
心して
Get ready, Tachibana.
橘 備えろ
Okay.
うん
-Now!
（白石･雄哉）せ〜の
（アイコ）ああああ！
This is the last place I visited
with my father.
（アイコ）
お父さんと一緒に最後に来た場所
This is where Mom and Ryota are.
お母さんと亮太(りょうた)がいる場所
It's where the disaster began.
（遙香）災厄の始まりの場所
Primary Point.
（雄哉）プライマリー･ポイントだ
（地響き）
あっ！
What? It's already moving?
（楓）えっ もう動き始めた！
Go!
（相模）行くぞ
The entrance is clogged with Matter.
（白石）
入口周辺は
マターで埋め尽くされてる
We'll enter through
the water intake and climb the shaft.
（雄哉）
取水口から揚水棟へ入り
シャフトを登る
From there, we'll head to the bottom
of the facility,
上層部から施設内を最下層へ下り
最終目的地
多目的手術装置アルサスへ向かう
and head for our final destination,
the surgical system, ALSUS.
あ…
Things are looking bad,
Director Nanbara.
（堀(ほり)）
いよいよヤバい感じです
南原局長
The opposition party is permitting
limited use of weapons
野党が自衛隊の武器使用について
爆心地周辺に限定することで
歩み寄りを見せました
by the Self-Defense Forces
within Ground Zero.
（楓）さて いよいよ本拠地
Okay, we're finally here.
あっ
橘！
Tachibana!
That's the place!
（アイコ）あの場所だ
Dad...
お父さん
私 必ずお母さんと亮太
助けるから
I swear that I'll save Mom and Ryota.
The root of all the Matter.
The origin of the Burst.
（雄哉）
すべてのマターの根源
バーストの始まり
Our target is the bottom level.
目指すのは あの最下層だ
よし 行くぞ
Okay, let's go!
Aiko!
（館内放送）アイコ君
（一同）あっ…
You know not to leave
the hospital like that.
ダメじゃないか
病院から抜け出しちゃ
Who's that?
（楓）誰？
Dr. Isazu?
（アイコ）伊佐津先生？
（伊佐津）
戻っておいで
Come back.
I won't do anything to make you unhappy,
私なら君を不幸にしたりはしない
その転校生君と違って
unlike that transfer student.
（雄哉）あっ
Kanzaki?
神崎君？
I know him well.
（伊佐津）
彼のことは よく知っているよ
And I know why he has taken you there.
君をそこに連れていった目的も
I never thought we would be able to
talk like this again.
またこうして
話ができるとは思わなかったよ
久しぶりだな
It's been a long time,
Toshihide Yura.
由良俊英(ゆらとしひで)
（アイコ）ん？
（白石）あっ…
（アイコ）え？
What?
（一同）え？
Toshihide Yura... That can't be!
（遙香）由良俊英… まさか
Who's that?
（楓）誰？ それ
You don't know?
（一樹）知らないのかよ
He's the genius who invented
that Live Suit you've got on!
お前が着てるライブスーツとかの
大元(おおもと)を発明した天才
（楓）えっ マジ？ こいつが？
Seriously? This guy?
No way. He died in the Burst.
（相模）
んなわけ…
バーストんときに死んだはずじゃ
Dr. Isazu, what are you saying?
伊佐津先生 何 変なこと…
He survived.
（伊佐津）
生き逃れていたんだよ 彼は
え？
（伊佐津）
神崎雄哉という
見ず知らずの少年の複製体に
By transplanting his own brain
into the duplicate body
of a boy he never knew, Yuya Kanzaki.
自らの脳を移植することで
The serial number
of the sacrificed duplicate body is
犠牲となった
哀れな複製体のシリアルは
20210001
20210001.
（一同）あっ…
（遙香）失礼
Excuse me.
NAME: YUYA KANZAKI
複製体シリアル 20210001
Artificial organism
serial number 20210001.
This is Artificial Organism
duplicate body Unit One.
人工生体による複製体 第一号
（アイコ）え？
Isazu,
（雄哉）伊佐津さん
what's the point in revealing that secret?
その謎解きは誰の得にもならない
（相模）マジかよ
This can't be real.
（一樹）だから何でも知ってるのか
No wonder he knows everything.
（アイコ）あっ…
（黒瀬）あちゃ〜
Damn!
You mean we didn't delete all the data?
（小春）
消し損ねたデータがあった
ってこと？
Was it on a standalone server?
まさかスタンドアローン？
That old Kiryu's security
was way too tight.
セキュリティ 堅すぎるぜ
桐生のおやじさんよ
Hey, hold on here!
ちょっと あなた
You knew Toshihide Yura was alive?
由良俊英が生きていること
知ってたの？
知ってたも何も 俺が移植手術を…
I didn't just know.
I performed the transplant.
Why didn't you tell me?
どうして黙ってたの！
言えば あいつをエリアに
入れるなんて危険なミッション
If I did, you never would have
let him enter the Area
on such a dangerous mission.
絶対 阻止しただろ？
あっ…
（伊佐津）
皆は知っているのかな
Did you all know
that the surgery that man there
performed on Aiko Tachibana
その目の前の男が
橘アイコ君に施した手術によって
was the cause of the Burst.
バーストが引き起こされたことを
（一樹）
えっ アイコちゃんの手術？
Aiko's surgery?
You caused the Burst?
（相模）お前がバーストを？
I bet there's one more thing
you didn't know, Aiko.
それじゃあ ひょっとして
アイコ君も聞いてなかったのかな？
To end the Burst,
バーストを終息させるには
君の脳と君自身の本当の体が
抹消されなければならない
your brain and your body
must be destroyed.
ということを
え？
（一同）え？
But...
（アイコ）えっ？ でも
The fake one will be destroyed!
消えるのは作り物のほう
That's right.
（伊佐津）
そのとおりだ
はっ！
The fake one is me?
作り物は… 私のほう
Is that right?
そうなの？
Kanzaki!
神崎君！
（アイコ）あっ！
What's this?
（アイコ）
えっ… 何？
Where is this?
どこ？ ここ
私だ　ケガしてる
That's me. I'm injured.
Oh, right. I was in a car accident.
そっか 交通事故
And Dr. Yura performed the surgery.
で 由良先生が手術を
What? Then why do I see myself?
あれ？ でも どうして 私
自分を見てるんだろう
How is it I'm able to see myself?
自分が見えてるんだろう
Is it true?
（白石）本当なの？
Aiko Tachibana's duplicate body panicked
複製体の橘アイコのボディは
分離された本来の脳を求めて
パニックを起こし 異常増殖
when its brain was removed,
and underwent abnormal cell proliferation,
creating the Malignant Matter.
マリグナント･マター化した
That was the Burst.
それがバーストだ
In other words, your body is the Matter.
つまりマターこそが君の体
For you to return to your body
君が自分の体を
取り戻すということは
means that you must become the Matter.
すなわち
マターになるということだよ
私がマターに？
I'll become the Matter?
For Yura to end the Burst,
he'll induce apoptosis in your brain.
由良はバーストを終息させるため
君の脳にアポトーシス
In other words, he'll cause your cells
to commit suicide
つまり細胞の自殺を誘発する―
by injecting you with a medication
called Anti-Cell Assembler.
アンチ･セル･アセンブラという
薬剤を投与するつもりだ
Then, he'll return your brain
to the artificial organism body
そして その脳を
人工生体の体に返すことで
so it annihilates your body
that has turned into the Matter.
マター化した君の体を
死滅させようとしている
To him, your brain
彼にとって君の脳は
is nothing more than a tool
to save the real Aiko Tachibana.
本物の橘アイコを救うための
道具にしかすぎない
However, I don't want to lose you.
だが 私は君を失いたくはない
That's because
なぜなら 君は
you are the only artificial organism brain
世界で唯一の意識を宿した
人工生体頭脳なのだから
that has ever obtained consciousness.
もうすぐエリア内のマターを
焼き尽くすため
Soon, the Self-Defense Forces
will attack the Matter
自衛隊が攻撃を開始する
in the Area to wipe it out.
-What?
（一同）え？
（伊佐津）
それまでに研究所対岸の地下にある
ハザードシェルターに退避して
If you evacuate to the hazard shelter
in the basement
on the opposite side of the facility
until the attack is over,
攻撃をやり過ごせば
you'll survive.
君は生き残れる
Come back to me...
戻っておいで 私の所に…
なっ… うっ
I cut the communication,
but it'll be back online before long.
通信 切ったけど
復旧されるのは時間の問題
For Yuzuha's sake, he plans to prevent
Yura from ending the Burst.
柚葉ちゃんのためなら
バースト終息も阻止すると
恐らく
So it seems.
（ため息）
とりあえず由良俊英を
生かしておいてくれたことには
At any rate, I appreciate that
you saved the life of Toshihide Yura,
感謝するわ
and that you told me
Isazu's true intentions.
伊佐津の本音を
教えてくれたことにも
（黒瀬）なら
Then...
can you stop
the Self-Defense Forces' attack?
自衛隊の攻撃 止められないか？
Wait! There's a serial number on my eye!
あ！ でも 私 目に番号があった
Isn't that proof that this body
is the fake one?
それって この体が偽物だっていう
証拠なんでしょ？
だったら…
Then...
（遙香）待って 見てあげる
Wait. I'll have a look.
データ共有します
I'll share the data.
There it is. Serial number 20210002.
あった　シリアル 20210002
２番目の複製体
It's duplicate body Unit Two.
じゃあ やっぱり
Then, I really am...
（楓）すごっ！
Amazing!
Then, that means... Shiraishi?
（一樹）
それじゃあ… あっ 白石さん？
（ダイバー達･アイコ）ん？
Shiraishi?
（アイコ）白石さん？
Shiraishi!
白石さん
（白石）あ…
Isn't that so, Shiraishi?
違うんですか？ 白石さん！
アイコちゃん 目は脳の一部なの
Aiko, your eyes are part of your brain.
What?
え？
Artificial organism eyes
are made as part of the brain.
（白石）
人工生体の眼球は
脳の一部として作るの
（アイコ）あっ…
That means if there's
an inscription on the eyes...
つまり眼球に
打刻があるということは…
アイコちゃん
Aiko,
あなたの脳が作り物だということ
it means that your brain is artificial.
はっ
（３人）えっ！
But it's impossible to introduce
carbon nanostructures into a real body!
（一樹）でも生身の体に
カーボン･ナノ･ストラクチャは
投与できないんだろ？
（遙香）完全な生身ならね
If it were an entirely real body.
（一樹）え？
If Cell Assembler Two was used
to repair her injuries during surgery,
（遙香）
手術の際に 体の損傷が
セル･アセンブラ２によって
修復されたのなら
then those parts
are artificial organisms.
その修復箇所は人工生体
So it would be possible
オリジナルであっても
for carbon nanostructures
to coexist with the original body.
カーボン･ナノ･ストラクチャとの
共存は可能ということになる
Am I wrong?
違うかしら？
You're exactly right.
（雄哉）そのとおりだ
（アイコ）あっ…
Then, when Isazu introduced that,
（黒瀬）
そして伊佐津が
それを投与したことが
it triggered the Burst.
バーストの引き金になった
（２人）えっ
I bet Isazu himself
doesn't even realize that.
伊佐津本人は
そのことに気付いてないがな
何 ひと事みたいに言ってんだよ
How can you act like it's nothing?
But I can think for myself!
I can feel! I have thoughts!
でも私 自分で考えてるし
感じてるし 思ってるよ
小さいときから
今までのことも覚えてる
I remember everything since I was a child!
So how can I still be a fake?
なのに それなのに偽物なの？
I created your mind
in order to save Aiko Tachibana.
君の脳は橘アイコを救うために
僕が生み出した
You're AICO, the Aiko Tachibana duplicate.
橘アイコの複製“ＡＩＣＯ(エーアイシーオー)”だ
（アイコ）はっ…
君の本当の体は
バーストを起こし
Your real body caused the Burst,
and became the Matter
that has overrun the Area.
エリア全体に はびこる
マターとなってしまった
The fault for that lies with me.
そして その責任は僕にある
And to take responsibility,
その責任を取るために
I will return you to where you belong.
僕は君を本来あるべき場所に戻し
I have to complete the treatment
of Aiko Tachibana.
橘アイコの治療を
完了させなければならない
（アイコ）え？ そ…
What? But...
Then let's get going! Merge her
with the Matter and end this Burst.
（相模）
なら とっとと マターと融合させて
バーストを終息させようぜ
（アイコ）あっ…
Damn! An artificial brain?
That's one crazy zombie.
ったく 脳みそが作り物って
何のゾンビだよ
Sagami!
相模さん！
Hey, kid, I think your words
are contradicting your actions.
（相模）お前
言ってることと やってることが
矛盾してねえか
What?
あ…
ん？
Oh, shit!
うわっ ヤバッ！
-Haruka, Evidence!
-Wait!
（楓）遙香 エビデンス！
（遙香）待って
Aiko, we have to escape!
（一樹）アイコちゃん 逃げなきゃ
（一樹）アイコちゃん！
（雄哉）橘！
-Aiko!
-Tachibana!
-Stop!
-Oh, no!
（一樹）待って！
（楓）ちょ…
Aiko!
（一樹）アイコちゃん！
Tachibana!
（雄哉）橘！
I want you to send a team to Primary Point
to retrieve Aiko Tachibana.
（伊佐津）
プライマリー･ポイントに
橘アイコの回収部隊を送ってほしい
Sorry, but I can't approve that.
（南原）
残念だけれど 承諾できないわね
手は打つわ
I'll see to this.
Can you leave it to my discretion?
私の裁量に
任せてもらえないかしら
（ため息）
I knew it. The only person
who can save you is me.
（伊佐津）
やっぱり お前を救えるのは
お父さんだけだ
ああ！
うう…
ああっ！
あっ…
Gummi?
グミ？
（グミ）キュキュウ〜
What?
え？
Thank you for coming.
（橘アイコ）来てくれてありがとう
（アイコ）はっ！
（グミ）キュキュ
Nice to meet you.
（橘アイコ）はじめまして
You're the other me.
もう１人の私
〜
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey